<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Startups for the Small Investor]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Startups for the Small Investor]]></description>
        <link>https://thegrid.ai/authentic-demand/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 23:29:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://thegrid.ai/authentic-demand/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Authentic demand: The ?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Authentic demand: The ?</h1><p>The word "authentic" is meant to raise a question. Is there something that startup founders see or experience, that appears to be demand but isn't?  </p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/authentic-demand/what-is-authentic-demand/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">aa60c5ae-f421-4e78-8548-ccbd39b79b17</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 23:29:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I have an idea and some interest from customers, a demo I had made, and a lot of drive, but no technical expertise.  Will a VC fund me without a technical cofounder?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>I have an idea and some interest from customers, a demo I had made, and a lot of drive, but no technical expertise.  Will a VC fund me without a technical cofounder?</h1><p>undefined</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/authentic-demand/i-have-an-idea-and-some-interest-from-customers-a-demo-i-ha/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">41ab50fe-9565-45d7-adba-9b9721db690e</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 22:37:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What do you do when your product has zero traction?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>What do you do when your product has zero traction?</h1><p>Except in a case where you've inherited responsibility for someone else's product, you should never have a product with zero traction.  

Spend all of your startup time trying to figure out the customers.  You've got to learn a secret about them.  Not the thing they think is cool or useful. Not the thing they say they want - the secret isn't about an object, it's about them.  It can't be discovered by asking them.  It can't be discovered by showing them an MVP and gauging their reaction.  It'll take the following form: How they go about being who they are, is this.  They are prevented from being that thing by this.  

Ultimately, your product will be the thing that overcomes the thing that prevents them from being who they are.  If this is your product, it will reliably find traction.  The reaction this type of product gets is "authentic demand.  But don't worry about that at the beginning.  Thinking about product first screws you up.  

Most people will answer you with a trick or an inspirational story, or direct you to Ben Horowitz's book.    But the answer isn't perseverance.  Persevering with a product that won't sell reliably is a mistake.  Save your perseverance for working on understanding the customer until you really do.  Use your perseverance to stop yourself from just going with something that you think will work.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/authentic-demand/what-do-you-do-when-your-product-has-zero-traction/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">3ad8c804-0b2c-41a0-b128-8e03411f09bb</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 23:01:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What are the "must take" steps for an early stage startup?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>What are the "must take" steps for an early stage startup?</h1><p>This is a fantastic question, but an unanswerable one.  The problem is that startups, to have any chance of succeeding, must attach to the world of their customers in an innovative way.  The other two options - attaching to the world of the customers in a known, tried and true way, or not attaching at all - are both failure paths.   If you do it in a tried and true way, then your business is a minnow in direct competition with whales.  Your competitors have a thousand times your resources, experience, relationships, brand value, customer habit, money, technology know-how, etcetera, and you have nothing special.  You can make this work in a protected little niche, or for a while, but it doesn't scale and isn't safe. </p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/authentic-demand/what-are-the-must-take-steps-for-an-early-stage-startup/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2355efaf-3a0e-42e9-a720-bff1881a131d</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 22:35:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>What numbers should be included in a pitch deck?</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/authentic-demand/8f29f92b-3a00-4c47-a2eb-2d8eed411ffa/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">8f29f92b-3a00-4c47-a2eb-2d8eed411ffa</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 22:51:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Can capitalist societies overcome poverty?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Can capitalist societies overcome poverty?</h1><p>Absolutely! </p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/authentic-demand/can-capitalist-societies-overcome-poverty/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">1bdee72e-89d7-4033-a2af-00bcd23869fe</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 22:12:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is it possible to raise seed funding before launching a product?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Is it possible to raise seed funding before launching a product?</h1><p>Yes.  As you reduce risks you make it more possible to raise money, and at a higher valuation.  Having an idea doesn't do much to reduce risk.  Having launched a product shows that you've reduced the risk that you weren't actually able to produce a product.  Having launched a product that's selling well reduces a lot more risk.  Before you do that, you can reduce risks by having team members who've done it before, through prototypes, and through some kind of market validation that appears valid to the investor.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/authentic-demand/is-it-possible-to-raise-seed-funding-before-launching-a-prod/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">51ee3ad0-0665-4b93-a48a-8b34cd801342</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 19:13:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What do investors think of Kanye West's $1 Billion "ask?"]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>What do investors think of Kanye West's $1 Billion "ask?"</h1><p>I'm much too small an investor to be one of those being asked. But for what it's worth,  I think that West, a very talented artist, should seek mental health counseling.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/authentic-demand/what-do-investors-think-of-kanye-wests-dollar1-billion-ask/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">154419ee-becb-47ec-8304-bcb5a2c01f86</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 19:10:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How do seed investors decide whether a company will become a unicorn?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>How do seed investors decide whether a company will become a unicorn?</h1><p>Well, here's how I try to do it:

Act like Odysseus passing the sirens.*</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/authentic-demand/how-do-seed-investors-decide-whether-a-company-will-become-a/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">29b4b64a-f1e9-4b08-bf05-60dd8108c479</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 19:06:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How do accelerators make a profit?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>How do accelerators make a profit?</h1><p>Most accelerators lose money.  The revenue producing models fall into a few categories: </p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/authentic-demand/how-do-accelerators-make-a-profit/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">91e01a48-998f-44a2-820e-8689cf13b5c0</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 18:58:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>