<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Authentic Demand]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Authentic Demand]]></description>
        <link>https://thegrid.ai/authentic-demand/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 22:51:13 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://thegrid.ai/authentic-demand/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What is authentic demand?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>What is authentic demand?</h1><p>The word "authentic" is meant to raise a question. Is there something that startup founders see or experience, that appears to be demand but isn't?  </p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/authentic-demand/what-is-authentic-demand/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">aa60c5ae-f421-4e78-8548-ccbd39b79b17</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 22:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What are the "must take" steps for an early stage startup?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>What are the "must take" steps for an early stage startup?</h1><p>This is a fantastic question, but an unanswerable one.  The problem is that startups, to have any chance of succeeding, must attach to the world of their customers in an innovative way.  The other two options - attaching to the world of the customers in a known, tried and true way, or not attaching at all - are both failure paths.   If you do it in a tried and true way, then your business is a minnow in direct competition with whales.  Your competitors have a thousand times your resources, experience, relationships, brand value, customer habit, money, technology know-how, etcetera, and you have nothing special.  You can make this work in a protected little niche, or for a while, but it doesn't scale and isn't safe. </p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/authentic-demand/what-are-the-must-take-steps-for-an-early-stage-startup/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2355efaf-3a0e-42e9-a720-bff1881a131d</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 22:35:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>What numbers should be included in a pitch deck?</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/authentic-demand/8f29f92b-3a00-4c47-a2eb-2d8eed411ffa/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">8f29f92b-3a00-4c47-a2eb-2d8eed411ffa</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 22:51:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Can capitalist societies overcome poverty?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Can capitalist societies overcome poverty?</h1><p>Absolutely! </p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/authentic-demand/can-capitalist-societies-overcome-poverty/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">1bdee72e-89d7-4033-a2af-00bcd23869fe</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 22:12:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is it possible to raise seed funding before launching a product?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Is it possible to raise seed funding before launching a product?</h1><p>Yes.  As you reduce risks you make it more possible to raise money, and at a higher valuation.  Having an idea doesn't do much to reduce risk.  Having launched a product shows that you've reduced the risk that you weren't actually able to produce a product.  Having launched a product that's selling well reduces a lot more risk.  Before you do that, you can reduce risks by having team members who've done it before, through prototypes, and through some kind of market validation that appears valid to the investor.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/authentic-demand/is-it-possible-to-raise-seed-funding-before-launching-a-prod/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">51ee3ad0-0665-4b93-a48a-8b34cd801342</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 19:13:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What do investors think of Kanye West's $1 Billion "ask?"]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>What do investors think of Kanye West's $1 Billion "ask?"</h1><p>I'm much too small an investor to be one of those being asked. But for what it's worth,  I think that West, a very talented artist, should seek mental health counseling.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/authentic-demand/what-do-investors-think-of-kanye-wests-dollar1-billion-ask/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">154419ee-becb-47ec-8304-bcb5a2c01f86</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 19:10:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How do seed investors decide whether a company will become a unicorn?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>How do seed investors decide whether a company will become a unicorn?</h1><p>Well, here's how I try to do it:

Act like Odysseus passing the sirens.*</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/authentic-demand/how-do-seed-investors-decide-whether-a-company-will-become-a/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">29b4b64a-f1e9-4b08-bf05-60dd8108c479</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 19:06:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How do accelerators make a profit?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>How do accelerators make a profit?</h1><p>Most accelerators lose money.  The revenue producing models fall into a few categories: </p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/authentic-demand/how-do-accelerators-make-a-profit/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">91e01a48-998f-44a2-820e-8689cf13b5c0</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 18:58:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why should a CEO deserve more equity than a co-founder acting as a consultant?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Why should a CEO deserve more equity than a co-founder acting as a consultant?</h1><p>Think of a startup company as a journey or adventure. Whose adventure is it?  Who is the protagonist of this story?  Normally it's the CEO.  Investors, particularly angels, are people who want to accompany the protagonist on their journey. One thing they're interested in is that the protagonist is committed to making the journey, pushing forward wherever it leads (unless/until it's absolutely clear that it leads nowhere.) That's why you need a CEO and that's why the CEO is incented with a stake in the company. </p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/authentic-demand/why-should-a-ceo-deserve-more-equity-than-a-co-founder-actin/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">b2523702-ea64-4ae4-98d3-38dd3312fc92</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 18:51:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I'm a technical founder.  How much equity should I give up to investors?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>I'm a technical founder.  How much equity should I give up to investors?</h1><p>The key here is to think of this not in terms of what's right for you or for the investors, but what's right for the company.  This is too much equity for a first investor, and will probably kill your business. The cap table will be lopsided and new investors won't come in later. However, it's likely that the issue here is not really equity but control.
The details you provide indicate that you're thinking as a technical person rather than a business person.  This is a challenge for an investor, because he or she will know that without a leader who's talented, focused, and experienced on the business side your company will fail no matter how useful the technology might be. 
So,  if I was an expert in your area and loved the technology so much that I didn't want to miss the opportunity, I'd want controlling interest in the company so I had control over your business decisions. 
There are two scenarios where this might make sense, and one (more likely) scenario where it doesn't. 
The investor comes in to run the business as a cofounder.  They might be the right person and partner to do that. 
It's a strategic investor, a company that already makes and sells similar products; they're essentially buying your technology and adding it to their portfolio.
The investor thinks you might be an ok CEO, but they don't trust you in that role and want to be able to make the decisions and tell you what to do.
Scenario three will probably lead to failure.  Scenarios 1 and 2 could work, depending on you.
Your alternative options include:
Find a business cofounder yourself, work together for a while, and then raise money.
Convince another investor that you're a good business person to run this.
Propose a deal to this investor that they get less equity but get preferred shares in a structure that gives them control.
If you're like most people, you'll prefer #1 or #2, but it's worth listening to investors who think you're not the right person to run the company.  One of my most successful investments was a company with a great technical founder, and also a great salesman, who investors did not believe would be a good CEO.  Part of how he convinced investors to come in was by demoting himself to chief scientist and bringing in a CEO.  That showed maturity, knowledge of his strengths and weaknesses, humility, and an ability to work with people.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/authentic-demand/im-a-technical-founder-how-much-equity-should-i-give-up-t/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">a88bea24-6916-4242-af65-0b06c73ab9a3</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 18:49:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>